Vikash Sehwag

Ph.D. Candidate Princeton University, Princeton, NJ 08544

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in research problems in the domain of trustworthy machine learning. Some topics I have worked on are adversarial robust supervised/self-supervised learning, improving robustness using generative models, adversarial robustness in compressed neural networks, open-world machine learning, self-supervised detection of outliers, robust outlier detection, privacy leakage in large scale deep learning, and faster-federated learning.

EDUCATION

Program	Institution	Years
Ph.D., Electrical and Computer Engineering Advisors – Prateek Mittal, Mung Chiang	Princeton University NJ, USA	2017 - Present
M.A., Electrical Engineering	Princeton University NJ, USA	2017 - 2019
B.Tech., Electronics and Electrical Communication Engg.	Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Kharagpur, INDIA	2013 - 2017

HONORS AND AWARDS

• Best paper honorable mention award at ICLR workshop on Security and Safety in ML Systems	2021
• Winner of Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship, North America Region	2019
• Received a departmental nomination for Microsoft Research PhD Fellowship	2019
• Received best undergraduate thesis award (1 from 72 students) at IIT Kharagpur	2017
• IEEE student award from IEEE student branch of IIT Kharagpur	2016
• Awarded the WISE scholarship from German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD), Germany	2016
• Received Merit-cum-Means Scholarship from MHRD, Government of India	2013-17

WORK EXPERIENCE

•	Research Internship – $Facebook\ AI$, USA	Summer 2021
	Advisors – Caner Hazirbas, Cristian Canton Ferrer	
	Project: Generating novel hard instances from low-density regions using generative models.	
•	Research Internship – Microsoft Research, USA	Summer 2019
	Advisors – Jay Stokes, Cha Zhang	
	<i>Project</i> : Adversarial attacks and defenses beyond ℓ_p norms	
•	Research Assistant – IIT Kharagpur, India	Fall 2016
	Advisors – Indrajit Chakrabarti, Santanu Chattopadhyay	
	Project: Implementing physical unclonable functions with Network-on-chip routers	
•	Research Internship – Technische Universität Darmstadt, Germany	Summer 2016
	Advisor – Heinz Koeppl	

Project: A study of stochastic SIS disease spreading on random graphs

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Teaching • Lecture on basics of adversarial machine learning at Princeton-Intel REU Seminar	2021			
• Teaching assistant for ECE 574: Security & Privacy	Fall 2021			
• Taught a mini-course on adversarial attacks & defenses in Wintersession at Princeton Un	niversity 2020			
\bullet Teaching assistant for ECE 535: Machine Learning and Pattern Recognition	Fall 2019			
Mentoring				
I continue to mentor the next generation of researchers.				
• Edoardo Debenedetti - Master's student at École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EF	PFL) 2021-now			
• Christian Cianfarani - Graduate Student at University of Chicago.	2021-now			
• Rajvardhan Oak - Master's student at University of California, Berkeley	Summer 2020			
• Tinashe Handina (B.S.E., Electrical Engineering 2021) - now a graduate student at Calt				
• Matteo Russo (B.S.E., Computer Science 2020) - now a PhD candiate at University of California, Berkele				
	, ,			
Peer reviewing	2022			
• Transactions on Machine Learning Research (TMLR)	2022			
• International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	2022			
• International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)	2022			
• Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	2022			
• International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)	2022			
• Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2021			
Privacy Enhancing Technologies Symposium (PETS) Output	2021, 2022			
• Conference on Information Sciences and Systems (CISS)	2020, 2022			
PLOS Computational Biology ACM TO DE COMPUTATION OF THE PROPERTY OF THE	2020			
• ACM Transactions on Privacy and Security (TOPS)	2019			
• USENIX Security Symposium	2018, 2019			
Other Services				
• Part of core maintaining team of Adversarial Robustness Benchmark (robustbench.githul	b.io) 2020-now			
• Volunteered for beta-testing of OpenReview submission pipeline for upcoming TMLR jou	urnal 2022			
• Volunteered as junior mentor at Princeton-OLCF-NVIDIA GPU Hackathon	2020			
Invited Talks				
• A generative approach to robust machine learning (link) RIKEN-AIP TrustML Young Scientist Seminar, Japan	Jan 2022			
• Generating novel hard-instances form low-density regions using generative models Facebook AI, USA	Aug 2021			
• A primer on adversarial machine learning Princeton-Intel REU Seminar	July 2021			
• Embedding data distribution to make machine learning more reliable Adversarial robustness seminar, École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)	March 2021			
• Private Deep Learning Made Practical Qualcomm, San Diego	Oct 2019			

PUBLICATIONS

Conference and Journal Publications

- Generating High Fidelity Data from Low-density Regions using Diffusion Models Vikash Sehwag, Caner Hazirbas, Albert Gordo, Firat Ozgenel, Cristian Canton Ferrer Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022
- Robust Learning Meets Generative Models: Can Proxy Distributions Improve Adversarial Robustness?
 Vikash Sehwag, Saeed Mahloujifar, Tinashe Handina, Sihui Dai, Chong Xiang, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022
- RobustBench: a standardized adversarial robustness benchmark
 Francesco Croce*, Maksym Andriushchenko*, Vikash Sehwag*, Edoardo Debenedetti*, Nicolas Flammarion,
 Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal, Matthias Hein
 Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021 Datasets and Benchmarks Track
 Won best paper honorable mention prize at ICLR 2021 workshop on Security and Safety in Machine Learning
 Systems.
- Lower Bounds on Cross-Entropy Loss in the Presence of Test-time Adversaries Arjun Nitin Bhagoji, Daniel Cullina, Vikash Sehwag, Prateek Mittal International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2021
- SSD: A Unified Framework for Self-Supervised Outlier Detection
 Vikash Sehwag, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal
 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021
 Short version accepted at NeurIPS 2020 Workshop on Self-Supervised Learning Theory and Practice
- Beyond ℓ_p Norms: Delving Deeper into Robustness to Physical Image Transformations Vikash Sehwag, Jay Stokes, Cha Zhang *IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)*, 2021
- PatchGuard: Provable Defense against Adversarial Patches Using Masks on Small Receptive Fields Chong Xiang, Arjun Nitin Bhagoji, Vikash Sehwag, Prateek Mittal USENIX Security Symposium, 2021
- HYDRA: Pruning Adversarially Robust Neural Networks
 Vikash Sehwag, Shiqi Wang, Prateek Mittal, Suman Jana
 Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020
- Fast-Convergent Federated Learning

Hung T. Nguyen, Vikash Sehwag, Seyyedali Hosseinalipour, Christopher G. Brinton, Mung Chiang, H. Vincent Poor IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications (J-SAC) - Series on Machine Learning for Communications and Networks, 2020

Peer-reviewed Workshop Publications

- Robustness from Perception
 - Saeed Mahloujifar, Chong Xiang, Vikash Sehwag, Sihui Dai, Prateek Mittal ICLR workshop on Security and Safety in Machine Learning Systems, 2021
- Time for a Background Check! Uncovering the impact of Background Features on Deep Neural Networks Vikash Sehwag, Rajvardhan Oak, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal ICML workshop on Object-Oriented Learning, 2020
- On separability of self-supervised representations Vikash Sehwag, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal ICML workshop on Uncertainty & Robustness in Deep Learning, 2020
- On Pruning Adversarially Robust Neural Networks
 Vikash Sehwag, Shiqi Wang, Prateek Mittal, Suman Jana
 ICLR workshop on Towards Trustworthy ML, 2020

 $^{^{*}}$ refers to equal contribution.

- Analyzing the robustness of open-world machine learning
 Vikash Sehwag*, Arjun Nitin Bhagoji*, Liwei Song*, Chawin Sitawarin, Daniel Cullina, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal
 In Proceedings of the 12th ACM Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Security (AISec), 2019
- Not All Pixels are Born Equal: An Analysis of Evasion Attacks under Locality Constraints Vikash Sehwag, Chawin Sitawarin, Arjun Nitin Bhagoji, Arsalan Mosenia, Mung Chiang, Prateek Mittal Poster at ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2018.